imagine the square numbers represented
by square arrays of Cubes like these
then what we have here is a depiction of
the sum 1 squared up to N squared
especially when we stack them on top of
one another like this to form a square
pyramidal array now take two extra
copies of this pyramidal array rotate
one of them twice and the other one
three times like this then the three
copies of the pyramidal array fit
together to form a shape that is almost
a cuboid but has an extra half top layer
now we can take a second copy of this
almost cuboid and consider its Mirror
Image this means we've used six copies
of the sum of the first n squares we can
glue these two almost cuboids together
to form a cuboid whose dimensions are n
by n plus one by two n plus one
therefore the sum of the first n squares
is equal to n times n plus one times two
n plus one divided by six